Lemonade Mouth is a drama, comedy, music film directed by Patricia Riggen.
When five ragtag freshman first meet in detention, it
seems they have nothing in common.
But, through music, they form an unbreakable bond and discover they have the
makings of the greatest high school garage band in history!
In the face of incredible odds, Olivia, Stella, Wen, Mohini and Charlie find they can make a real difference
when they learn to lean on each other and let go of everything holding back their dreams.
Olivia, played by Bridgit Mendler.
Charlie, played by Blake Michael.
Wen, played by Adam Hicks.
Stella, played by Hayley Kiyoko.
Mohini, played by Naomi Scott.
Scott, played by Nick Roux.
Lemonade Mouth is a 2011 American musical comedy drama television film produced by and
aired on Disney Channel as one of the network's original films (DCOM).
Based on Mark Peter Hughes's 2007 novel of the same name, the film was
directed by Patricia Riggen and written by April Blair.
It stars Bridgit Mendler, Adam Hicks, Naomi Scott, Hayley Kiyoko and Blake Michael as five high school students who meet in
detention and form a band to stand up for their values and to overcome their individual and collective struggles.
Lemonade Mouth became the third most-watched DCOM premiere of its year with 5.7
million views, and DVR viewing raised the number to 7.1 million.
The film earned a Popstar!
Poptastic Award and nominations at the Directors
Guild of America and Golden Reel Awards.
Its soundtrack reached number four on the Billboard 200 and produced the
Billboard Hot 100 singles "Somebody", "Determinate" and "Breakthrough".
Lemonade Mouth received positive reviews from critics and audiences,
with praise for its direction, performances and themes.
In the years following its release, it has been
considered one of the best DCOM films.
The film explores themes of guitar, parent child
relationship, cat, violin, narration.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.